<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Optional on HPC on IBM Cloud Tutorials</title><link>//ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/tags/optional/</link><description>Recent content in Optional on HPC on IBM Cloud Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 15:49:49 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/tags/optional/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Standing up an LSF Cluster</title><link>//ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/02-setup-lsf-cluster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/02-setup-lsf-cluster/</guid><description>IBM Spectrum LSF is part of the HPC Clustering Services on IBM Cloud to enable users to stand up a HPC environment within minutes. LSF is an advanced workload management solution for demanding HPC environments. HPC cluster deployment starts with the definition of the desired cluster configuration; for example, count of management nodes, worker nodes, amount of storage and so on. Open-source technologies like Terraform and Ansible have been used to automate the provisioning and configuration of all associated IBM Cloud VPC resources and LSF.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Bursting</title><link>//ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/03-bursting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/03-bursting/</guid><description>IBM Cloud offers virtual private clouds (VPCs), which enable elastic provisioning of x86 virtual servers with the pay-as-you-go model. Users can optimize both the cost and performance of their target workloads by maintaining the number of virtual servers and their resource configurations. VPCs support various instance flavors of virtual machines with from 1 to 128 virtual CPUs, from 4GB to 1TB RAM, and various capacity and performance settings of storage and networking.</description></item><item><title>Custom Image</title><link>//ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/04-custom-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 15:49:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>//ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/04-custom-image/</guid><description>In this tutorial, we will guide you through the steps to create a custom image that allows you to install custom software packages and later reuse the image for creating new LSF clusters. We assume you have followed the steps in &amp;lt;02-setup-lsf-cluster&amp;gt; to create an existing LSF cluster, and we will reuse its VPC infrastructure to create a VSI within it.</description></item></channel></rss>