<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>burst on HPC on IBM Cloud Tutorials</title><link>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/tags/burst/</link><description>Recent content in burst on HPC on IBM Cloud Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 01:00:00 -0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/tags/burst/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Set up VPN</title><link>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/03-bursting/01-vpn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 01:00:00 -0100</pubDate><guid>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/03-bursting/01-vpn/</guid><description>The automation package is implemented as a Terraform template for VPCs on IBM Cloud. Users can configure and start their cluster creation with Schematics, a Terraform platform with Web UI on IBM Cloud. The template is publicly available at GitHub for IBM Cloud. All you need to create a cloud HPC cluster is to set the GitHub link to a Schematics workspace, edit pre-defined variables, and click several buttons. This tutorial gives a step-by-step guide to creating an example VPN deployment.</description></item><item><title>Set up multi-cluster and job forwarding</title><link>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/03-bursting/02-setup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 01:00:00 -0100</pubDate><guid>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/03-bursting/02-setup/</guid><description>Set up the LSF multi-cluster and job forwarding. This tutorial assumes that the small on-premise cluster labeled with &amp;ldquo;OnPremiseCluster&amp;rdquo; uses a subnet 192.168.3.0/24. The cluster runs a master node at 192.168.3.21 (on-premise-master) and two single-CPU workers (i.e., up to two CPUs are available for jobs). The cloud cluster labeled with &amp;ldquo;HPCCluster&amp;rdquo; uses a subnet 10.248.0.32/27 and its master uses 10.248.0.37 (icgen2host-10-248-0-37) without any static workers created. Both of the configuration directories are in /opt/ibm/lsf/conf, but you can change the directory depending on your cluster configuration.</description></item><item><title>Try cloud bursting</title><link>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/03-bursting/03-tryout/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 01:00:00 -0100</pubDate><guid>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/03-bursting/03-tryout/</guid><description>Now you can forward jobs from on-premises to the cloud. This tutorial tries to request three CPUs by starting three concurrent sleep 10s although the example on-premise cluster has only two CPUs. At your on-premises cluster, you can test the following command:
$ for i in `seq 1 3`; do bsub -q send_q sleep 10s; done The cloud cluster needs a few minutes to allocate a dynamic host. After a while, you can check if cloud bursting works at on-premise-master.</description></item></channel></rss>