<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Standing up an LSF Cluster on HPC on IBM Cloud Tutorials</title><link>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/02-setup-lsf-cluster/</link><description>Recent content in Standing up an LSF Cluster on HPC on IBM Cloud Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/02-setup-lsf-cluster/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prepare SSH and API Keys</title><link>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/02-setup-lsf-cluster/01-sshkey-api/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 10:01:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/02-setup-lsf-cluster/01-sshkey-api/</guid><description>Create Your SSH KEY After you sign in to https://cloud.ibm.com/ with your account, start with the Navigation Menu on the dashboard in the top left corner of the page:
Click VPC Infrastructure &amp;gt; SSH Keys
Click Create
Add name (e.g. demo-ssh-key), type your resource group name and select region Copy the public key and paste it in the public_key field(e.g.: contents in .ssh/id_rsa.pub) Click on Add SSH Key If you do not have SSH keys on your machine where you plan to log in to your HPC cluster, use the ssh-keygen command to generate.</description></item><item><title>Create Your Cluster using IBM Spectrum LSF</title><link>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/02-setup-lsf-cluster/02-hpc-cluster-catalog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 10:05:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/02-setup-lsf-cluster/02-hpc-cluster-catalog/</guid><description>After you sign in to https://cloud.ibm.com/ with your account, search &amp;ldquo;HPC&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Spectrum LSF&amp;rdquo; in IBM Cloud catalog. Find &amp;ldquo;IBM Spectrum LSF&amp;rdquo; and select the service. It will lead you to the HPC Cluster solution page. Or the tile can be directly accessed from here.
Scroll down to the Configure your workspace section. The resource group parameter in this section is where the Schematics workspace is provisioned on your IBM Cloud account.</description></item><item><title>Access Your Cluster</title><link>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/02-setup-lsf-cluster/03-access-cluster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 10:03:16 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/02-setup-lsf-cluster/03-access-cluster/</guid><description>Overview of the HPC Cluster The HPC Cluster consists of a login node, a storage node where the block storage volume is being attached to, 1 to 3 LSF management nodes, and a number of LSF worker nodes.
The login node is served as a jump host and it is the only node which has the public IP address. Other nodes would only have private IP addresses and the only way to reach to these nodes is through the login node.</description></item><item><title>Run LSF Jobs Using Auto-Scaling</title><link>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/02-setup-lsf-cluster/04-run-job/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 10:03:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/02-setup-lsf-cluster/04-run-job/</guid><description>worker_node_max_count and _worker_node_min_count are the parameters for you to configure auto-scaling. If you leave worker_node_max_count and _worker_node_min_count parameters with default values, you currently would have no worker node in your cluster.
In the example below, icgen2host-10-242-64-37 is the only node in your LSF cluser and is served as the LSF management node which is configured not to run users&amp;rsquo; workloads.
[lsfadmin@icgen2host-10-242-64-37 ~]$ bhosts -w HOST_NAME STATUS JL/U MAX NJOBS RUN SSUSP USUSP RSV icgen2host-10-242-64-37 closed_Full - 0 0 0 0 0 0 In addition, since the worker_node_max_count parameter is set to 10, you can only submit jobs that use no more than 10 nodes.</description></item><item><title>Manage your Cluster</title><link>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/02-setup-lsf-cluster/05-manage-cluster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 10:03:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ibm.github.io/ibmcloud-hpc-tutorials/02-setup-lsf-cluster/05-manage-cluster/</guid><description>You can manage your VPC resources in the Schematics workspace. You can use Resources in the menu on the left to visualize all the resources created for your HPC cluster. The cluster configuration parameters will be listed when you click Settings. When you are ready to destroy your cluster, you can use Actions &amp;gt; Destroy resources to destroy your cluster. If you no longer want to keep the workspace, you can select Delete workspace instead.</description></item></channel></rss>